Guide to the Durham Savoyards (Durham, N.C.) Records, 1898-1989 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Durham Savoyards (Durham, N.C.) records 1898-1989 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Durham Savoyards, Ltd.
9.5 Linear Feet Approximately 6043 Items
Durham, N.C. production company of Gilbert and Sullivan operettas, founded in 1963 and incorporated in 1964.
Collection contains the archives of the Durham Savoyards and consists of minutes, correspondence, programs, financial records, posters, director's notes, stage design, photographs, videocassettes, color slides, and clippings, dating from 1898 to 1989. Two writings are also included: "The Savoyards, Durham Savoyards Limited, 1989" and "Mindful of the Whys and Wherefores," a Savoyard producer's journal by James Parmentier. There are a few photos that pre-date the founding of the Savoyards. They picture comic operas said to have been given at the Southern Conservatory of Music in Durham.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Use copies must be made before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Durham Savoyards (Durham, N.C.) Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library between 1976 and 1998.
Historical Note
The Durham Savoyards are a Durham, N.C. production company of Gilbert and Sullivan operettas, founded in 1963 and incorporated in 1964.
Collection Overview
Collection contains the archives of the Durham Savoyards and consist of minutes, correspondence, programs, financial records, posters, director's notes, stage design, photographs, videocassettes, color slides, and clippings, dating from 1898 to 1989. Two writings are also included: "The Savoyards, Durham Savoyards Limited, 1989" and "Mindful of the Whys and Wherefores; a Savoyard Producer's Journal" by James L. Parmentier. There are a few photographs that pre-date the founding of the Savoyards in 1963. They picture comic operas said to have been given at the Southern Conservatory of Music in Durham.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Gilbert, W. S. (William Schwenck), 1836-1911
Music -- Societies, etc.--North Carolina -- Durham
Musicals -- Production and direction
Operetta -- North Carolina -- Durham
Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900. Operas
Contents of Collection
- Printed Material Series, (5 boxes)
  - Pictures [photographs] (Box 1)
  - Membership cards
  - A-G (Box 2)
  - H-L (Box 3)
  - M-Pa (Box 4)
  - Pi-Y (Box 5)
- Productions Series (Acc. 1-22-87), 1973-1982, (5 boxes)
  - Yeoman of the Guard, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Gondolier, 1974
  - Trial by Jury, 1975
  - Princess Ida, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Iolanthe, 1976
  - Pirates of Penzance, 1978 (Box 3)
  - The Mikado, 1982
  - H.M.S. Pinafore, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Oversize Material, (1 box)
  Oversize publicity posters and clippings relating to various Savoyards productions
  Set Design for Sorcerer, 1979
  set Design for Iolanthe, 1976
  Check in poster for Ruddigore, 1979
  Drawings for set of Ruddigore[?], undated
  - Oversize files, (5 folders) (Box 6)
- Addition (12/12/87), 1981-1983, (2 boxes)
  Contains correspondence, notes, programs, printed material, clippings and other material related to Utopia, The Mikado and the Durham Savoyards 20th reunion.
- Addition (90-001), (1 box)
  Videocassettes of performances, mainly Pirates of Penzance.
- Addition (92-015), (1 box)
  Notebook for the production The Sorcerer, 1989. Contains notes, reviews, calendars, correspondence, libretto, and other materials. Also contains Mindful of the Whys and Wherefores; a Savoyard producer's journal by James L. Parmentier.
- Addition (98-312), 1967-1985, (2 boxes)
  Contains correspondence, financial papers, director's notes for shows, publicity, minutes for board of director's meetings, and production information, including casting and budget details.